oh thank you to be here for this talk
哦，谢谢你来这里演讲
about like configuration management with
关于类似的配置管理
kubernetes I know that kubernetes like
kubernetes我知道kubernetes喜欢
it super popular but this is a spring
它超级受欢迎，但这是春天
boots conference so I will try to apply
靴子会议，所以我会尝试申请
the conferring called kubernetes
被称为kubernetes的会议
recipients to to spring boots I'm Nicola
收件人到春天的靴子我是尼古拉
Frankel this is actually my second
弗兰克尔这实际上是我的第二个
spring I oh I was in like two or three
春天我哦，我就像两三个
years ago I don't remember I've been
年前我不记得我去过
doing consulting work for more than 17
做超过17项咨询工作
years in the like as a Java developer
作为Java开发人员多年
architect position and six months ago I
建筑师的职位，六个月前我
decided that it was much better to be
决定要好得多
paid to go to conferences do talks I've
付费参加会议做演讲
beer meet people it's a good way to earn
啤酒满足人们，这是一种赚钱的好方法
money I've always been interested in
我一直很感兴趣的钱
about like what is be beyond the wall
就像墙外的东西
you know that there is a dev and the up
你知道有一个开发者
space and if you are the who here is a
空间，如果你是谁，这里是一个
developer okay nearly everyone huh after
开发人员好吧，几乎所有人
you you create the package then it's not
您创建软件包后，它不是
your problem anymore you you send it
您的问题了，再发送给您
afterwards and whatever happens happens
之后，无论发生什么
I don't know why I was already
我不知道为什么我已经
interested in what happens afterwards so
对之后发生的事情感兴趣
my first thought you're like and
我的第一个念头就是
previous in addition was about the
之前的内容是关于
spring boot actuator which is a very
弹簧启动执行器
super nice piece of engineering and
超级棒的工程和
today to be about kubernetes I work at
今天是关于我工作的kubernetes
the company called eggs of scale we are
公司叫做规模蛋
European cloud provider who doesn't use
不使用的欧洲云提供商
the cloud yet everybody does who is
云，但每个人都做谁
using the cloud who is using Amazon yeah
使用谁正在使用亚马逊的云
Google yeah Asia Microsoft Asia ok so
Google是的，亚洲，微软，亚洲，好的
all those nice company there are
所有那些不错的公司
American company and who knows about the
美国公司，谁知道
cloud act hahaha a few hands and of
云动哈哈哈几手和
course in less than all we used the
当然少于我们使用的所有
cloud the cloud act is a US law but
云法是美国法律，但
which supplies worldwide just like GDP
就像GDP一样供应全世界
ah but
啊但是
verse and it tells you that if you
诗句告诉你，如果你
contract with an American company the US
与美国公司签约
government can access your data anywhere
政府可以在任何地方访问您的数据
in the world even if you contract like
即使你像
here like my data center is in Barcelona
就像我的数据中心在巴塞罗那一样
whatever if you value the data of your
如果您重视自己的数据
customer if you value your own data I
客户，如果您重视自己的数据，我
encourage you to look at the cloud act
鼓励你看云行为
to understand what in details what the
了解什么细节
consequences are and and to check
结果是and和检查
European cloud providers anyway so this
反正欧洲云提供商如此
is what you can find on Wikipedia about
您可以在Wikipedia上找到有关
configuration management so it's a super
配置管理，这是一个超级
nice piece of text telling you very
一段很好的文字告诉你
general terms in general when you think
当您认为时，一般术语
about configuration management's you
关于配置管理的你
think about those and of course the
想想那些，当然
first step of configuration management
配置管理的第一步
is scripts you try to make your life
是您试图使自己的生活脚本
easier by creating scripts but for one
通过创建脚本更容易，但是对于一个
machine for two machines for five
两台机器，五台机器
machines it might work after some point
可能会在某些时候工作的机器
however you notice that that doesn't
但是你注意到那不是
scale because then you have a lot of
扩展规模，因为那时你有很多
machine and now we are in an era where
机器，现在我们处于一个时代
we don't have light server as pets we
我们没有像宠物一样的小型服务器
have kettles when something doesn't work
当无法正常工作时要烧水壶
we killed them we will launch them and
我们杀死了他们，我们将发射他们，
we want to make sure that those are the
我们要确保这些是
same that we're before I remember some
就像我们之前记得的一样
years ago something happened in
多年前发生了什么事
production and though we deploy to like
生产，虽然我们部署喜欢
three production before we didn't notice
三个生产之前我们没有注意到
it and then my question but why I mean
然后是我的问题，但为什么我的意思是
the environment was supposed to be the
环境应该是
same but of course it wasn't you
一样，但是当然不是
couldn't do manually keep your
无法手动保留您的
configuration like the same and so there
像一样的配置等等
are like a lot of new tools like puppet
就像很多新工具一样
chef soul state and Sybil whatever that
厨师的灵魂状态和西比尔
are supposed to do that for you who here
应该为你在这里做的
is a configuration management user not
是配置管理用户，不是
that many people puppet chef and Sibyl
这么多人偶厨师和西比尔
and that's funny ok now I always add a
这很有趣，现在我总是添加一个
problem
问题
ansible because once I understood puppet
Ansible，因为一旦我了解了p
and chef it was very hard for me to get
和厨师对我来说很难
back to the like typing commands because
回到类似的键入命令，因为
what what would you do when
你什么时候会做什么
configuration management is that
配置管理是
basically you said you describe you
基本上你说你描述你
declare the state of the system and you
声明系统状态，您
want the system to be in and then you
希望系统处于运行状态，然后您
trust the configuration management tool
信任配置管理工具
to keep that system in this state and of
使该系统保持这种状态
course you system will drift and then
当然你的系统会漂移，然后
it's the role of a configuration
这是配置的角色
management tool to always like push it
总是喜欢推的管理工具
back to where it was that's what the
回到原来的地方
power of other like declarative
陈述式的力量
configuration management is and outcomes
配置管理是和结果
communities and you don't have this
社区，你没有这个
problem anymore because you have
问题了，因为你有
immutable images wherever you are using
无论您在哪里使用，图像都是不变的
docker or not images they are mutable so
码头工人或不是他们可变的图像，所以
they are not supposed to change so what
他们不应该改变，那么
the point of configuration management in
配置管理的重点
that case the problem is the same image
这种情况下，问题是同一张图片
needs to be deployed in different
需要部署在不同的位置
environments so even if the image is
环境，即使图像是
immutable it should be configured in
不可变，应在
different ways like before you had the
像以前一样的不同方式
war and you deployed it into Tomcat and
战争，然后将其部署到Tomcat中，
of course if you deployed it in
当然，如果您将其部署在
development environment or in like
开发环境或类似
staging environments the database
暂存环境数据库
arrival was not the same so though your
到达是不一样的，所以尽管你
war was immutable
战争是一成不变的
you needed to configure in some way and
您需要以某种方式进行配置，
for that if you used WebSphere or Tomcat
为此，如果您使用WebSphere或Tomcat
yeah some people used WebSphere believe
是的，有人用WebSphere相信
me well you could configure the symbolic
我很好，你可以配置符号
link to real database data source
链接到真实的数据库数据源
depending on your environment there are
根据您的环境
still a few seats left here if you don't
如果不这样做，这里还有几个座位
want to stand though you want to stand
想站立，虽然你想站立
okay that's fine too so we have the same
好，那也很好，所以我们有相同的
probe
探测
we've docker images we want them to be
我们有docker镜像我们希望它们成为
immutable but we still want them to like
一成不变，但我们仍然希望他们喜欢
be configurable depending on your
可配置，具体取决于您
environment and for that there is a very
环境，为此，有一个非常
simple use case you deploy your
部署您的简单用例
application in different environments
在不同环境中的应用
and then you are in the test environment
然后您处于测试环境中
and you want to reset the whole database
而您想重置整个数据库
because you want to like run your tests
因为你想运行测试
so you go to the application you remove
所以你去删除的应用程序
every user depending on the user
每个用户取决于用户
interface and then you notice a I was on
界面，然后您注意到我在
production it never happened to you
生产它从未发生在你身上
right so previously how we address that
对，所以以前我们如何解决
and probably you still do is that
可能您仍然这样做
depending on the environment you have a
根据您所处的环境
banner with the name of the environment
带有环境名称的横幅
on top of it
在它的上面
who does it already so I guess all the
谁已经做过，所以我猜所有
others they don't it's a good idea think
其他人不是，这是个好主意
about it
关于它
so in production of course you have no
所以在生产中您当然没有
banner it's the good stuff but then in
横幅是好东西，但随后
every environment then you have this
每个环境，那么你有这个
banner and the name and that's a perfect
标语和名称，这是一个完美的选择
use case for us because then we have the
用例，因为我们有
same application and we deploy it to
同一应用程序，我们将其部署到
different environment and then we get
不同的环境，然后我们得到
that so I've talked enough now let's do
这样，我已经说了足够多了，让我们做
some demo stuff so I've created an
一些演示的东西，所以我创建了一个
application existing application on
应用程序上现有的应用程序
spring on star dot spring dot IO I have
我在星点上弹弹簧
a simple controller that like redirects
一个喜欢重定向的简单控制器
me to a family of templates and on the
我来一整套模板，并在
time leaf template I have like I get the
我喜欢的时间叶模板
label and I get the color and if the
标签，我得到的颜色，如果
label and the color I show them if there
标签和颜色（如果有的话）
is no label and no color of course I
没有标签，当然没有颜色
don't show anything so I will just show
什么都不要显示，所以我只显示
you how it works without any profile or
您如何在没有任何个人资料的情况下工作，或
anything just like out of the blue
像天翻地覆的一切
yes start the stuff and then I can show
是的，开始工作，然后我可以展示
you how good a designer I am and then
你我是多么优秀的设计师，然后
you understand why I am a back-end
你明白我为什么是后端
engineer
工程师
see very great that's basically what I
看到非常好，这基本上就是我
want to have in production but then in
想要投入生产，然后投入生产
the front of my mind I want to show
我想展现的心意
something else so one of the easiest way
其他一些最简单的方法之一
to achieve that is basically to create
实现基本上就是创造
profiles I want to create profiles and
我要创建配置文件的配置文件
so I have a dev profile and when this
所以我有一个开发人员资料
profile is activated I want to have the
个人资料已激活，我想拥有
yellow development banner and when this
黄色发展旗帜，何时
is activated I have the staging orange
已激活，我有暂存橙色
stuff okay so let's try it so you might
东西还好，让我们尝试一下，这样您就可以
know about like spring boots the first
首先知道像春靴
thing to do is I will get the
要做的是我会得到
environments so private and vironment
如此私人和环境化的环境
and I will make it final and then I can
然后我将其定型，然后我可以
get those keys AB dot and dot color
得到那些键AB点和点颜色
and label and then I pass that to the
和标签，然后我将其传递给
model right
示范权
so normally what should happen here yeah
所以通常在这里会发生什么
I'm sorry that it's a session where you
抱歉，这是你的会议
should work what happens now
应该工作现在发生了什么
Thanks nothing happens nothing happens
谢谢，什么都没有发生
which is what I want because I it's the
这是我想要的，因为我是
default profile its production so now I
默认配置文件的生产，所以现在我
will activate the staging profile and
将激活登台配置文件并
normally I didn't check I hope I check
通常我没有检查我希望我检查
the stuff here it's def profile yep so
这里的东西是def profile是的
it works a easy-peasy it's done however
它很容易完成，但是
you might object that a getting the
您可能会反对
environment it's not super great because
环境不是很好，因为
then we get the whole stuff so perhaps
然后我们得到全部东西，也许
it might be better to ever live
活下去可能会更好
individual keys so this can be done also
个别按键，因此也可以完成
by annotating and injecting not value
通过注释和注入价值
color like that though also here I will
像这样的颜色虽然我也会在这里
just copy paste at
只需将粘贴复制到
and level and level and normally if I
和水平和水平，如果我
reset that I will change to have like
重置我将更改为
staging just to make sure that it's not
只是为了确保不是
a cache or anything
缓存或其他任何东西
yep it works but I mean it would be hard
是的，它有效，但我的意思是很难
to test if I won't like to have like an
测试我是否不喜欢
integration test I need to get the hold
集成测试我需要掌握
of a private field so injecting
私有领域的注入
bye-bye-bye field is not super great so
再见再见领域不是很好，所以
one of the the other option that we have
我们拥有的另一个选择之一
is to create like direct properties I
是要创建像直接属性一样
can create a dedicated class and ever
可以创建专门的课程
create application environment
创建应用程序环境
properties and then I don't remember the
属性，然后我不记得了
name its conflict props yes so here I'd
命名它的冲突道具是的，所以我在这里
with a class I just mimic the structure
在课堂上我只是模仿结构
of the yellow file and then
黄色文件，然后
automatically magically and of course
自动神奇地，当然
because I annotated them then at startup
因为我在启动时给它们加了注释
time like spring will read the Yamal
像春天一样的时间会读亚马尔
file and we'll put the yam the values
文件，我们将山药的值
into this class so now I just need to
进入这堂课，所以我现在只需要
get back to my my private final
回到我的私人决赛
application abandoned properties props
应用废弃属性道具
and I can do dot drops dot yet and of
我可以做点滴点和
God yet color now oh not get close get
上帝还没有变色哦
color and sends your props dot kit and
上色并发送道具套件和
thought get level and here I only have
想得到水平，这里我只有
the values that I need in a neatly
我整齐地需要的价值观
injectable class so that you can light
注射类，以便您可以点燃
integration tests wherever you want and
集成测试，无论您在何处
now it works again great perfect
现在它再次完美
everything is fine now we have something
一切都很好，现在我们有了东西
that works how do we do that with
起作用了，我们如何做到这一点
kubernetes well the first thing to do is
kubernetes做的第一件事就是
actually to create the deployment file
实际上创建部署文件
so I will create a new ml file
所以我将创建一个新的ml文件
Cades deploy dot yellow and here I will
卡德斯部署点黄，我会在这里
like create very easy
喜欢创建非常容易
my deployment I'm so fast yeah I know
我的部署速度非常快，是的，我知道
so first I will create a namespace
所以首先我将创建一个名称空间
because like you do your code in
因为就像您在执行代码一样
packages here I create my my deployment
包在这里我创建我的部署
in a very specific place so I create a
在一个非常具体的地方，所以我创建了一个
namespace and the second section is
命名空间，第二部分是
about the service because you know that
关于服务的信息，因为您知道
by default whatever happens inside a
默认情况下，
kubernetes cluster stays in the
kubernetes集群停留在
kubernetes cluster yeah you knew about
你知道的kubernetes集群
las vegas but it's the same here so if
拉斯维加斯，但是这里是一样的，如果
you want to access the kubernetes
您想访问kubernetes
cluster you need to give like an entry
您需要像输入一样给集群
points and there are several into entry
点，有几个进入
points available the easiest one to use
可用积分最容易使用
at least for for testing is not pores so
至少用于测试不是毛孔，所以
that means that I will give the IP the
这意味着我将给IP
local IP of the club kubernetes cluster
俱乐部kubernetes集群的本地IP
and this port number and I will be able
和这个端口号，我将能够
to access the single code inside and
访问其中的单个代码
finally I have a single port which is
最后我有一个单一的端口是
good enough for our needs and I deploy
足以满足我们的需求，我部署
my application but so far I don't have
我的申请，但到目前为止我还没有
any container to deploy I just have like
我要部署的任何容器
my application for that what you can do
我的申请表
is you can add the G plug-in and I
您可以添加G插件吗​​？
encourage you to look at the G plugin
鼓励您看一下G插件
it's really great it's a plugin meant by
真的很棒，它是一个插件，
Google and you don't need to create a
Google，您无需创建一个
docker image the G plug-in takes care of
docker镜像G插件负责
it for you so it will just check the
它给你，所以它只会检查
main class and out of the main class it
主要阶级和主要阶级之外
will create the docker image with all
将创建所有的docker镜像
the required towards and all the
对所有的要求
compiled classes and all the resources
编译的类和所有资源
that is super super great and you have
那是超级超级伟大，你有
like two goals available the first one
像有两个目标，第一个
is basically you
基本上就是你
your image to the registry so by default
您的图像到注册表，所以默认情况下
is the docker hub registry but you can
是docker hub注册表，但您可以
configure it with credentials and blah
用凭据配置等等
blah blah or here what I will be doing I
等等等等，或者我将要做什么
will just be sending it to the local
只会将其发送到本地
docker daemon which means I don't have a
docker daemon，这意味着我没有
round trip to push and then to prove
来回推，然后证明
very very useful as you can see it is
如您所见，它非常有用
just like the classes themselves and the
就像班级本身和
jaws that are darker eyes
眼睛较黑的下巴
I don't create a drawer out of the
我不从中创建抽屉
application so now normally if I docker
应用程序，所以现在正常，如果我码头工人
images grep config mg mg and config and
映像grep config mg mg和config以及
it's taking ages I don't know why I have
我不知道为什么我有
trouble with that sorry okay let's
麻烦对不起，让我们
forget believe me they are here so what
忘记相信我，他们在这里，那又怎样
I want now I want to deploy it so I will
我现在想部署它，所以我会
be deploying it and to deploy that too
进行部署并进行部署
sorry to schedule that because in in
不好意思安排，因为在
kubernetes you schedule images on pods I
您在Kubernetes上调度图像I
will apply the file that I've just
将应用我刚刚的文件
created and the namespace was already
创建并且名称空间已经
created the service was like already
创建服务就像已经
created the only new thing is the
创造的唯一新事物是
application and now I have my
应用程序，现在我有了我的
application running on kubernetes and I
我和kubernetes上运行的应用程序
just need to get the IP so I'm running
只需获取IP，即可运行
on mini cube so I need to get the IP of
在迷你立方体上，所以我需要获取IP
mini cube and as I told you I just need
迷你立方体，正如我告诉你的，我只需要
to
至
there is one zero too much here okay so
这里有一个零太多了，所以
now is how do I get my banner if
现在是如何获得我的横幅，如果
necessary well we have created profiles
我们已经创建好了必要的资料
so let's use the profiles and actually
所以让我们使用配置文件
inside of until G the profile is just a
直到G里面的轮廓只是一个
checkbox but normally the profile is
复选框，但通常配置文件是
just like inaugurates an additional
就像开创了一个额外的
argument to the command line after the
命令行后的参数
main class so to do that we will do
主班这样我们要做
exactly that we will just do like no
确切地说，我们只会做“不”
because I'm lazy I already prepared
因为我很懒我已经准备好了
everything here so I will add an
这里的一切，所以我会添加一个
additional argument to the command line
命令行的附加参数
just as Jib would do it and now if I so
就像Jib会做的那样，现在，如果我愿意
here I must remove the existing pot
在这里，我必须删除现有的锅
because I didn't use any fancy stuff so
因为我没有用任何花哨的东西
cube City that delete pod and its deploy
删除pod的多维数据集城市及其部署
so no delete pod sorry did pull the
所以没有删除吊舱抱歉没有拉
application of course so now it removes
应用程序，因此现在将其删除
the pot and it deploys another one so we
锅，它部署了另一个
can check that everything is still fine
可以检查一切都还好
yes it's running again and now we have
是的，它再次运行，现在我们有了
the banner so we have one single
横幅，所以我们只有一个
immutable image and then it's very easy
不变的图像，然后非常容易
by passing the profile as an argument to
通过将配置文件作为参数传递给
be like context-dependent
就像上下文相关
and it might be good enough for you in
这可能对你足够好了
most cases but the problem is what
大多数情况下，但问题是
happens if you are working for a company
如果您在公司工作会发生
that pins environments often if you
如果您经常固定环境
number of environment is small and
环境数量少
stable doesn't change so often that's
稳定不会经常改变
but every time you build a new
但是每次您构建新的
environment you create a new environment
您创建新环境的环境
that means that you need to create a
这意味着您需要创建一个
profile inside the image that means that
图像中的配置文件，这意味着
even if the image doesn't change because
即使图像没有改变，因为
of the code you will need to create a
代码，您将需要创建一个
new release to do to add a new profile
新版本以添加新的配置文件
so a new version for something that
所以新的东西
doesn't change it makes no sense so
不改变就没有意义了
another way to do that is actually to
另一种方法是
use system properties so instead of
使用系统属性，而不是
using profile what you can do is you can
使用个人资料，您可以做的是
like pass the values directly a system
像直接将值传递给系统
properties just let's try that locally
属性只是让我们在本地尝试
first
第一
it works so basically we just need to
它可以正常工作，所以我们只需要
change the arguments right yeah remember
改变论点，对，记得
you need to work a bit so right
你需要工作得很对
no no because actually the arguments
不不，因为实际上参数
they are after the command line the
他们在命令行之后
profile is after the command line but if
配置文件在命令行之后，但是如果
you want to pass system properties there
您想在那里传递系统属性
should be before the main class so that
应该在主要班级之前
means that you need to know about the
表示您需要了解
jib command line and to override it
臂架命令行并覆盖它
so it's possible but not super nice it's
所以有可能但不是很好
possible mm-hmm hide your happiness
可能会隐藏你的幸福
right now
马上
so now I should work I did like purple
所以现在我应该工作像紫色
and reproduction so now if we go on
和繁殖，所以现在如果我们继续
kubernetes cluster purple in production
kubernetes在生产中群集紫色
so this might be good enough for you but
所以这对你可能已经足够了，但是
actually jib was a nice abstraction we
实际上臂架是一个很好的抽象
didn't care about what it did about the
不在乎它对
command line about the class pass about
关于类传递的命令行
whatever now we need to understand what
现在我们需要了解什么
the docker image looks like and to do
码头工人形象看起来和要做
stuff that is below the abstraction now
现在低于抽象的东西
we need to get our hands dirty who likes
我们需要弄污喜欢的人
it yeah it might be good enough for your
是的，对您来说可能已经足够了
needs that's perfectly fine let's see
需求很好，让我们来看看
what we can do actually you might know
我们实际上可以做些什么，您可能知道
that you might not use system properties
您可能不使用系统属性
but environment variables instead then
但是环境变量代替了
we don't have any problem with the
我们没有任何问题
command line anymore
命令行了
choose
选择
you
您
ah too soon
啊，太早了
No hey there is always the demo effect
不，嘿总有演示效果
so it works and much better because now
所以它工作得更好，因为现在
we keep the abstraction but yeah I'm
我们保留了抽象，但是是的，我是
sorry I like I stepped on my glasses so
对不起，我喜欢戴眼镜，所以
basically below the first line I see on
基本上在我看到的第一行以下
your blur and you are just sitting in
你的模糊，你只是坐在
the front row so I need to address to
第一排，所以我需要解决
someone I mean wasn't staging supposed
我的意思是没有上演
to be arranged
被安排
or you don't remember already well the
否则您可能已经记不清了
problem with that is basically if light
问题基本上是如果光
variables parameter whatever you call
变量参数无论您调用什么
them are dependent on each other you
他们彼此依赖
might do this kind of mistake because
可能会犯这种错误，因为
whatever happens happens so it would be
不管发生什么事
great if we had like again like an
很棒，如果我们又像一个
abstraction map a data structure to put
抽象映射要放置的数据结构
all the variables that what we need into
我们需要的所有变量
like a single place and that's good
就像一个地方，那很好
because if you know about kubernetes
因为如果您了解kubernetes
there is something called config map and
有一些叫做config map和
config Mac basically is just that it's
config Mac基本上就是
just a map key value pairs with a name
只是一个映射键值对和一个名称
and then you can reference this map from
然后您可以从
your container so instead of having end
您的容器，而不是结束
we have something called and from and so
我们有一个叫做and from的东西
we get to those like environment values
我们得到那些喜欢环境价值的东西
from a config map so now we are nicely
从配置图，所以现在我们很好
isolated and I need to run it because
孤立，我需要运行它，因为
otherwise you won't believe me we are
否则你不会相信我
again we keep our like gyp abstraction
再次，我们保持我们的gyp抽象
layer we are nicely isolated and we have
层，我们很好地隔离，我们有
our environment in one single place that
我们的环境集中在一个地方
we can reference and which has a
我们可以参考，其中有一个
semantics
语义学
it's called like HD so we know it's
就像高清一样，所以我们知道
staging you cannot make mistakes about
分阶段你不能犯错误
that what we always can but let's say
那我们总是可以的，但让我们说
you reduce the probability back again
你再次降低了概率
who is happy with that and also quite
谁对此感到满意，也很
happy but now you must think okay but
很高兴，但是现在你必须考虑好的
who is like creating the maps and
就像创建地图一样
updating the maps and creating new maps
更新地图并创建新地图
and stuff and perhaps in your company
和东西，也许在你的公司
sorry there is a kubernetes
抱歉，有一个kubernetes
administrator and there are developers
管理员，还有开发人员
and perhaps they don't share the same
也许他们不共享相同的
access rights they have like different
他们拥有不同的访问权限
life cycle different ways of working
生命周期不同的工作方式
well let's say it's in one word you are
好吧，说一句话，你就是
not develops so perhaps you want to
没有发展，所以也许你想
leave to the developer a way that they
留给开发商的方式
can update those values without managing
可以更新这些值而无需管理
kubernetes at all so let's remove the
完全是kubernetes，所以我们删除
config map let's put that in comment
配置图，让我们在评论中
because I will need it later and what we
因为我以后会需要它，还有我们
can do is we can say let's put those
可以做的就是说
values into a git repository and get
值放入git存储库并获取
repository this is a real of the
仓库，这是真实的
developers so they can push whenever
开发人员，以便他们可以随时随地进行推送
they want
他们要
now it becomes a bit more complex but
现在它变得有点复杂，但是
only marginally so here I've created
只有一点点，所以我在这里创建
something called the get container get
称为get容器get的东西
an init container and by contract the
初始化容器并通过合同
init container will run successfully
初始化容器将成功运行
before any of the image in the pod will
在广告连播中的任何图片之前
start of course if the init container
如果初始化容器，则当然开始
fails then nothing will start it can
失败，那么什么也不会启动
happen but if it does then that means
发生，但如果这样做，则意味着
that whatever you did you can be sure in
无论您做什么，都可以确定
your container that you can like you can
您可以喜欢的容器
rely on it in that case I mean yes it's
在那种情况下依靠它我的意思是是的
a long command line but believe me I
长长的命令行，但相信我，我
just do a git clone of a repository of a
只是做一个仓库的git克隆
git repository and I put the stuff into
git存储库，我把东西放进去了
a config folder and because this config
一个配置文件夹，因为这个配置
folder is mounted to a common volume
文件夹已安装到公共卷
here and here what happens is that the
在这里和这里发生的是
content of the git repository will be
git存储库的内容将是
accessible in my Applications image and
可在我的应用程序图像中访问
it can use it and because I mapped it
它可以使用它，因为我已将其映射
and it has like a format that Springwood
它的格式像Springwood
knows how to read because you know that
知道如何读书，因为你知道
it can read stuff from slash config so
它可以从斜杠配置中读取内容，因此
not only environment variables not only
不仅环境变量
system property not only profiles but
系统属性不仅是配置文件，而且
also like files that are supposed to be
也像应该是
in a slash config folder then spring
在斜杠配置文件夹中，然后弹跳
boot can use those files
启动可以使用这些文件
so let's try it
所以让我们尝试一下
I don't trust it it's not scheduled yet
我不相信这还没有安排
yes it does still works
是的，它仍然有效
but now you might say okay but I might
但是现在你可能会说好的，但是我可能
want the same mechanism but I want to be
想要相同的机制，但我想成为
parameterised then we can use the config
参数化，那么我们可以使用配置
map from Fred previously
弗雷德以前的地图
mmm clone Trump's I will just use here
mmm clone Trump，我会在这里使用
no not that death so I've added an
不，不是那样的死亡，所以我添加了一个
additional layer of abstraction so that
附加的抽象层，以便
now my config map doesn't hold the value
现在我的配置图不包含该值
but just the environments and the
但是只是环境和
version and of course for that I need to
版本，当然我需要
pass it here who loves ya mo okay who
传递给谁，谁爱你呀，好，谁
hates XML I don't understand that really
讨厌XML我真的不明白
I mean yeah Mel is a Python of pro of
我的意思是，梅尔（Mel）是专业的Python
configuration files if you forget one
配置文件，如果您忘记了一个
space you have yeah here I'm super happy
太空，你有，我超级开心
to have intelligent tells me no you did
有智慧告诉我不，你做了
something bad otherwise and here I must
否则不好，在这里我必须
have this one really you don't like XML
真的有这个你不喜欢XML
I mean it has a grammar jason no grammar
我的意思是说它有语法Jason no grammar
yeah more whole no grammar must
是的，整个他妈的都没有语法必须
be told
被告知
and let's check that it has been
让我们检查一下
deployed yes it has been deployed and it
部署是，它已经部署并且
still works so normal is here if we
仍然可以正常工作，如果我们
change the value because I just want to
更改值，因为我只想
make sure that everything works if I do
确保一切正常
Dev and I keep the version because I
开发人员和我保留版本，因为我
have only a single version
只有一个版本
takes a bit of time
需要一点时间
yes I love it yes yeah I've been a
是的，我喜欢它，是的，我一直
consultant but I'm not bullshitting you
顾问，但我不是在欺负您
it really works it's not a whiteboard so
它确实有效，不是白板，所以
basically we have seen multiple ways to
基本上我们已经看到了多种方法
initialize and to configure your docker
初始化并配置您的docker
image that contains a spring with
包含弹簧的图像
application in the kubernetes cluster
kubernetes集群中的应用程序
the easiest way is profile no doubt
最简单的方法无疑是个人资料
about it
关于它
profile is the easiest way however if
配置文件是最简单的方法
your environments they are not stable
您的环境不稳定
they change a lot you must pin off on
他们改变了很多，你必须依靠
new environments every now and then it's
时不时的新环境
not the right solution because then you
不是正确的解决方案，因为那时您
will need to update the image and that's
将需要更新图像，那就是
what you don't want to do what we have
你不想做什么我们拥有的
seen afterwards is a perhaps it would
后来看到的也许是
just be easier to like add like system
就像添加系统一样容易
variables environment sorry yeah setting
变量环境对不起是的设置
variables system properties sorry but
变量系统属性抱歉，
then you need to know about the way that
那么您需要了解
jib launches your image and then you
臂架启动您的图像，然后您
need to align duplicate it and then you
需要将其对齐，然后您
need to change it it's not super
需要改变它不是超级
confortable you lose you lose the
安慰你输了你输了
abstraction the third way we have seen
我们看到的第三种抽象
is we can use environment variables it
我们可以使用环境变量吗
works pretty well we get the abstraction
效果很好，我们得到了抽象
again but you might mismatch if the
再次，但如果
values are dependent on one another you
值彼此依赖
may you might mismatch them and you
也许你可能不匹配他们，你
might you will do mistakes in that case
那样的话你会犯错吗
and of course the whole point of this is
当然，这的重点是
like to avoid mistakes then we have seen
想要避免错误，那么我们已经看到
that you can put everything that is
你可以把所有的东西
related in the config map and again that
在配置图中相关，再次
might work for you if you are in the dev
如果您在开发人员中，可能会为您工作
upsetting but if you have like very
沮丧，但如果你有非常喜欢
separated role if your developers don't
如果您的开发人员没有分开的角色
have access to that then in that case
在那种情况下可以访问
perhaps it's better to have an init
也许最好有一个init
container and the contract of the init
容器和初始化合同
container again is like you are sure
再次容器就像您确定
that it has run successfully because you
它已经成功运行，因为您
dot your other container into the sea in
将您的另一个容器点入海中
the same ports we have used a git
与我们使用git相同的端口
repository for that and then we can go
仓库，然后我们可以去
the whole nine yards
整个九码
like we add again a config map to
就像我们再次向其中添加配置映射
parameterize some of the git command
参数化一些git命令
that is run and
运行
at the end so you can read about my blog
最后，您可以阅读有关我的博客的信息
you can follow me on Twitter you can of
您可以在Twitter上关注我
course get the repository and work it
课程获取存储库并进行操作
out for yourself and and every step I
为自己，以及我的每一步
ever commit so you can see what is
曾经犯过，所以你可以看到是什么
changing between two commits and if you
在两次提交之间切换，如果
need to remember all I told you then
需要记住我当时告诉你的一切
I've written an article for you that
我为你写了一篇文章
goes into the same details as I've told
跟我讲的一样详细
here so now we have like 10 minutes for
在这里，所以现在我们有10分钟的时间
questions and I will be happy to answer
问题，我很乐意回答
them
他们
yeah there is one point oh there are so
是的，只有一点
many questions
许多问题
the gentleman may as a mic already hello
这位先生可能已经是麦克风了
so question is how is your approach
所以问题是你的方法如何
better over using spring cloud config
优于使用Spring Cloud Config
server it's another option it's a
服务器是另一种选择
complete different option basically what
完成不同的选择基本上是什么
I could have done here in one of the
我本可以在其中一个
option is basically to you to use
选项基本上是给你使用
kubernetes with a cool in it container
带有酷容器的kubernetes
to use spring config server
使用spring配置服务器
it depends with spring cloud config
这取决于Spring Cloud配置
which I must admit I never used
我必须承认我从未使用过
basically you don't need to use
基本上你不需要使用
kubernetes you all you use your own
kubernetes您自己使用的所有东西
stuff my approach is and it's not my
我的方法是什么，不是我的
approach is my approaches is not better
办法是我的办法不是更好
it's just that I give you a whole
只是我给你一个整体
palettes of possible choices and
可能的选择调色板
depending on your context on your use
取决于您使用的环境
case on your company on what you like
您喜欢的公司案例
and we dislike and what works for you
我们不喜欢什么对你有用
and not then you can choose whatever you
然后你就可以选择任何东西
want if your your spring cloud config
想要您的春季云配置
and you are happy about it then
然后你对此感到高兴
everything is fine there was a question
一切都很好，有一个问题
here
这里
here thanks
在这里谢谢
changing the values in runtime changing
在运行时更改中更改值
the values in runtime and the gate
运行时的值和门
repository
资料库
does reflect in our spring application
确实反映在我们的春季申请中
or not so know those values are not hot
还是不知道这些值并不热门
reloaded so if you change the values at
重新加载，所以如果您更改值
runtime you will still have the same
运行时，您仍然会拥有相同的
stuff what you can do however is you can
你可以做的事情就是你可以
like restart the container when
就像重新启动容器时
kubernetes detects a change so through a
kubernetes检测到更改，因此通过
dedicated kubernetes container you can
您可以使用专用的kubernetes容器
watch that the values are change or not
观察值是否更改
mmm and then you can like stop the pod
嗯，然后你就可以停止豆荚了
and restart a new one or start like
然后重新开始一个新的或开始像
changing your replica set if you're
如果您要更改副本集
using really replica set or deployments
使用真正的副本集或部署
or whatever if you want to bake that
或者如果你想烤的话
into spring boots I don't know how it
进入春季靴子，我不知道如何
can be done I don't know how it can be
可以做到，我不知道怎么回事
done it's interesting but probably you
做的很有趣，但也许你
can like catch like Stephanie Cole or
可以喜欢斯蒂芬妮·科尔（Stephanie Cole）或
the team they probably know about it
他们可能知道的团队
what I know is from the kubernetes point
我从Kubernetes的角度知道
of view you can like watch the changes
您可以喜欢观看的变化
and restart the pods with the new values
然后使用新值重新启动Pod
and if you have like any of your
如果你喜欢任何一个
deployments you can do that in a rolling
您可以滚动进行部署
update so that's fine too you have no no
更新，这样也很好，你也没有
no downtime how do you handle passwords
没有停机时间，您如何处理密码
there is a dedicated like config map
有一个专用的类似配置图
called secrets
被称为秘密
okay thank you for the presentation
好的，谢谢你的演讲
you're assuming at any point that
您在任何时候都假设
there's a dedicated coordinated
有专门的协调人
kubernetes file in its file yes
kubernetes文件在其文件中yes
pair environment because obviously you
配对环境，因为显然您
have the environment in all the options
在所有选项中都有环境
that we have seen that it's in that file
我们已经看到它在该文件中
so I've seen other alternatives like I
所以我看过其他类似的选择
have one single cover notice five
一份封面通知五张
I baked the image and the images has the
我烘烤了图像，并且图像具有
the properties per environment okay so
每个环境的属性都可以
another option with this that you have
你拥有的另一个选择
presented I think is that using helm
提出我认为是使用头盔
charts in order to to have templates of
图表以具有以下模板
the environment so at the end you have
环境，最后你有了
the the same file that you have but in a
与您拥有的文件相同，但位于
home charts manner and the environment
家庭图表的方式和环境
it's a variable yep so then you only
是可变的，所以那么你只
manage one quadrant is file there are I
管理一个象限是文件，我
mean there are multiple ways to handle
意味着有多种处理方式
this configuration file this was not the
这个配置文件不是
theme of this talk and to be honest I
演讲的主题，老实说，我
have seen so many ways to do that and it
已经看到了很多方法可以做到这一点，
seemed the company community hasn't
似乎公司社区还没有
found the real good way to do it so I
找到了真正的好方法，所以我
don't assume that there is a single file
不要以为只有一个文件
here in my demo it was like much easier
在我的演示中，这要容易得多
to have one single file but you can you
拥有一个文件，但是您可以
could have the namespace you know one
可能拥有您知道的名称空间
file you could have the service in
文件，您可以在其中提供服务
another file you could have the pod in a
另一个文件，您可以在其中放置广告连播
third file you could have like one pod
你可能想要的第三个文件
file per environment you can do whatever
每个环境的文件您可以做任何事情
you want I have no real good advice to
你想我没有真正好的建议
tell you but wait until there is a
告诉你，但是等到有一个
consensus somewhere it's I mean let's
共识是我的意思是
face it kubernetes is like very light
面对它kubernetes就像很轻
very early it in its lifecycle
在生命周期的早期
there are a lot of stuff that we need to
我们需要很多东西
understand how it works what's and
了解它是如何工作的，以及
basically we learn by failing so right
基本上，我们通过失败来学习
now I didn't fell enough to tell you a
现在我还不够堕落，无法告诉你
this is how you should do it I've seen
这就是我应该看到的
help charts that
帮助图表
so parameterize that's basically you to
所以参数化基本上就是你
understand nothing afterwards then there
后来什么都不懂
is customized and but don't take the
是自定义的，但不要
fact that I put everything into the same
我把所有东西都放在同一事实
file for the way you should do it
文件，你应该怎么做
it was just like only for demo purposes
就像只是为了演示而已
and then it's very nice then I push on
然后很好，然后我继续
gate you have everything in one file you
门将所有内容都保存在一个文件中
can see everything other questions
可以看到其他所有问题
everything was clear I it's lunchtime
一切都清楚了，我是午餐时间
right ok thank you very much
好吧，非常感谢你
[Applause]
[掌声]
[Music]
[音乐]